Gabriel Lucena

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil



gnllucena@gmail.com



+55 11 992585821



linkedin.com/in/gnllucena

Summary

Human being, lover of software development and games. I have over 12 years of experience in software development and architecture. I think software without tests is a dead software. I can't start a project without thinking about continuous integration and delivery and whether the user really needs what is being built.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

XP Inc.

Feb 2020 - Present (2 years 3 months +)

Working with the company's treasury to develop a platform that compiled XP's funds transactions to check the company health and leverage.

Distributed system to consume different sources of information with different technologies, containerization of applications, development of frontends, creation of unit and integrated tests and CI/CD configuration.



Technical Leader

Ticket

Jun 2017 - Feb 2020 (2 years 9 months)

Technical leadership of a team of 7 developers, 2 QAs and 2 analysts working on the construction of new APIs for Onboarding, Refunds and the new TicketShop ecommerce.

Active participant in architecture, devops, scope prioritization and delivery strategies.

Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery configuration and mindset implementation.

Application of continuous testing practices and architecture definition of 16 services of the Onboarding microservice (2000 daily new clients) and 25 services of the Refund microservice (2 billion reais monthly movement).

Applications built on the Docker platform with hosting in Kubenetes. Monitoring and management through the Rancher and Grafana tool powered by Zabbix.



🚾 Senior Software Engineer

Ticket

Jun 2013 - Jun 2017 (4 years 1 month)

Development of the accounting, inventory and payment order services, integration with several modules of the business ERP: Customers, Contracts, Payments and Accounting.

Development of WebAPIs and integrations with ASMX services and WSDLs. Sites developed with ASP.NET MVC and JQuery.

Senior Software Engineer

Liberty Mutual Insurance

Dec 2012 - Mar 2013 (4 months)

Migration of legacy CRM to a new service-oriented architecture (SOA).

Provision of services to partner companies and integration with the Salesforce cloud platform.



Programmer

Closel Services

Jul 2010 - Dec 2012 (2 years 6 months)

Conducting interviews with stakeholders, analyzing and solution development based on requirements obtained.

Development of e-commerce platforms and controls for banking correspondents.

Development with ASPNET MVC, WebForms, Javascript and JQuery.

Education



👢 Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia de São Paulo - IFSP

Bachelor's Degree, Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas 2009 - 2012

Skills

Solution Architecture • ASP.NET • Angular • Scrum • Padrões de design • Design Patterns • Microsoft .NET • ASP.NET MVC • JavaScript • C#